-Guys, guess what? -What?
-大伙們，你們猜怎麼了？ -什麼？
We're having a Halloween party!
我們要辦萬聖節派對
-Good! -Great!
-很好 -太棒了
-You have to wear a costume. -I can't make it.
-你們得變裝 -我沒辦法參加
Come on, it'll be fun.
少來了，一定會很好玩的
I'll be there. I have to wear a costume to my classes that day anyway.
我會去的 反正那天上課時我也要變裝
Tell me you're not gonna dress like a dinosaur.
告訴我 你不會打扮成恐龍
Not two years in a row.
我不會連續兩年那麼做
-I'll come, but I'm not dressing up. -You have to.
-我會去的，但我不會變裝 -你得變裝才行
No. Halloween is stupid. Dressing up, pretending to be someone you're not.
不，萬聖節太愚蠢了 變裝，假裝你是另一個人
You're an actor.
你是個演員
Ross, are you gonna bring Mona?
羅斯，你會帶蒙娜來嗎？
-I will. -The girl from the wedding?
-我會的 -你在婚禮上認識的那個女孩？
If she needs costume ideas, she could be a bikini model..
如果她需要變裝點子 她可以扮成比基尼模特兒…
or a slutty nurse, or a sexy cheerleader.
或風流護士 或性感啦啦隊長
Or Leatherface from Texas Chainsaw Massacre. No! Slutty Leatherface.
或是德州電鋸殺人狂裡的皮臉 不，還是風流皮臉好了
Wasn't Joey hitting on her too?
喬伊不也很喜歡她嗎？
That's right, he was hitting on her.
沒錯，他喜歡她
And I got her. I guess the better man won.
我把到她了 我猜最好的男人才能贏
Please don't take her from me.
拜託別把她搶走
The One With The Halloween Party
本集播出：萬聖節派對
rainystar壓制iPod-MP4
Ursula!
烏蘇拉
Wait. It's me, Phoebe.
等一下，是我，菲比
I thought there was a mirror there. Okay. Bye.
我還以為那裡有鏡子 好吧，再見
Wait a second!
等一下
So, what's new with you?
你還好嗎？
Nothing. I'm getting married next week.
我很好 下星期我就要結婚了
What?
什麼？
It'll be a small ceremony. Just family.
婚禮很簡單 我們只邀請家人觀禮
His.
他的家人
Okay.
好吧
I'm happy for you.
我為你感到高興
Wait. If you want to come, I guess that'd be okay.
等一下，如果你也想來的話 我猜應該沒關係
-Really? -Sure.
-真的嗎？ -當然
You could be my sister for the day.
你可以當我的妹妹一天
Yeah, okay.
好吧
My friends are having a party tonight, so you could come.
我朋友今晚要辦派對 你可以來參加
Maybe I could meet the guy.
或許我可以看看他
Well, I'm supposed to work tonight.
我今晚要上班
I'm supposed to be working now, so who cares!
我現在應該去上班 誰在乎呢？
-It's a costume party. -So that's why you're..
-那是化裝派對 -所以你才會…
No.
不
But thanks.
但謝謝
-You're supposed to wear a costume. -I am.
-你應該變裝的 -我有啊
I am a woman who spent money on a dress she wants to wear..
我扮成花錢 買心愛洋裝的女人…
because soon she won't fit into it.
因為很快地 她會穿不下它
I'm Catwoman, who wants the dress when you're too big for it.
我是貓女 如果你穿不下它，可以把它送給我
-Trick or treat! -Can I give out candy?
-不給糖就搗蛋 -我可以分糖果給他們嗎？
I want to be with kids. Since I got pregnant, I have maternal instincts.
我想跟孩子們打成一片 我懷孕後母性的直覺都跑出來了
-Trick or treat! -Just a minute!
-不給糖就搗蛋 -等一下
Look at you guys!
看看你們
-Wow! You are a very scary witch. -Thank you.
-哇，你是個可怕的巫婆 -謝謝
-And you are a very funny clown. -Thank you.
-你是個好笑的小丑 -謝謝
And you..
你…
are so in style right now.
非常符合現在的流行趨勢
I work at Ralph Lauren. The fall line has got this equestrian theme.
我在羅夫羅蘭的公司工作 今年秋天流行馬術主題
-Did you see the cover of Vogue..? -Could I just have the candy?
-你看過時尚雜誌的封面… -我可以拿糖果嗎？
Sure.
沒問題
Catwoman. So we meet again.
貓女，我們又見面了
So we do, Supergirl.
沒錯，女超人
It's me, Phoebe.
我是菲比
Monica, can I talk to you for a second?
摩妮卡 我能跟你談一談嗎？
I appreciate the costume.
謝謝你幫我找衣服
You did this to him?
你幫他找衣服？
I thought he'd love it.
我覺得他一定會喜歡
-He loves The Velveteen Rabbit. -That rabbit was brown and white.
-他喜歡毛毛兔 -那隻兔子是棕白相間
It was pink, or no bunny at all.
他們只剩下粉紅色的兔子裝
No bunny at all. Always no bunny at all!
沒有兔子裝 他們總是說沒有兔子裝
-You didn't dress up either? -Yes, I did. I'm Chandler.
-你也沒有變裝？ -不，我有，我扮成錢德
Dude, what happened?
兄弟，發生了什麼事？
How is that me?
我怎麼會是那個樣子？
I'm Chandler.
我是錢德
That is so you!
那真的很像你
-When have I ever done that? -When have I ever done that?
-我什麼時候會那樣？ -我什麼時候會那樣？
Trick or treat.
不給糖就搗蛋
-You're the prettiest ballerina ever. -Thank you.
-你是最漂亮的芭蕾舞孃 -謝謝
That deserves another candy.
我該再給你一顆糖果
Thank you.
謝謝
I have to say, that earns "two-two" pieces of candy.
我得說 我該再給你一些糖果
I love you!
我愛你
Honey, here, take it all.
甜心，通通拿去吧
Monica? We need more candy.
摩妮卡，糖果沒了
-There's only been four kids. -I know.
-剛剛只來了四個孩子 -我知道
But one said she loved me, so I gave her everything.
但有個孩子說她愛我 於是我全部都給她了
No wonder you're pregnant.
難怪你會懷孕
-What are you supposed to be? -Remember the satellite, Sputnik?
-你這次扮成什麼了？ -還記得史波尼克號衛星嗎？
Well, I'm a potato. Or a "spud"..
我扮成馬鈴薯或是「波特多」…
and these are my antenna.
這是我的天線
So Sputnik becomes..?
所以史波尼克變成了…
Spud-nik!
波特多尼克
Wow! I don't have the worst costume anymore.
哇 原來我不是變裝最失敗的人
All right! Ross came as doodie.
好吧，羅斯是團糞
-No, I'm not doodie. -No, space-doodie.
-不，我不是糞 -對，你是太空之糞
Okay, I'm Spud-nik.
好吧，我是波特多尼克
-You know, like Sputnik. -What's a Sputnik, doodie-man?
-我在模仿史波尼克 -什麼是史波尼克？傻瓜
Hey, sweetie.
嘿，甜心
-Aren't you gonna kiss me? -Okay.
-你不吻我嗎？ -好吧
But right after, you have to tell me who you are.
但我吻了你之後 你得告訴我你是誰
-Ursula? -Ursula's fiance?
-烏蘇拉？ -烏蘇拉的未婚夫？
You're the sister. I just slapped my future sister-in-law's ass.
你是她的妹妹 我剛剛打了我未來小姨子的屁股
Is your mother here? I could slap her on the butt.
你媽媽在這裡嗎？ 我可以打她的屁股
-My mother killed herself. -See, and I knew that.
-我媽自殺死掉了 -看吧，我就知道
Now I'm sweating.
我滿身大汗
I'm sweating. Now I'm saying look at me, I'm even sweatier. I should go.
我在流汗，看看我 我滿身大汗，我該走了
No. We'll start over.
不，我們從頭來過
-Hi, I'm Phoebe. -Eric.
-嗨，我是菲比 -我是艾力克
-Why are you looking at me like that? -Sweat's burning my eyes.
-你為什麼要那樣子看我？ -汗滴到我眼睛裡了
-Thank you. -There.
-謝謝 -拿去吧
-What are you? -There's no name for it.
-那是什麼？ -我不知道該怎麼說
I get nervous, and I sweat like crazy.
我一緊張就會滿身大汗
-No, I meant your costume. -I'm a solar system.
-不，我是指你的服裝 -我扮成太陽系
My second graders helped.
我的二年級學生幫我變裝
-I love the second grade. -Really?
-我喜歡二年級 -真的嗎？
It's much better than first grade, and definitely better than third.
它比一年級好多了 也比三年級好
With all the politics and the mind games.
你可以玩爾虞我詐 的鬥智遊戲
-So, what do you do? -I'm a masseuse, by day.
-你是做哪一行的？ -我白天時是按摩師
-You don't have to stand with me. -I'm having fun.
-你不必陪我 -我覺得很開心
-I'm excited for you and Ursula. -I feel very lucky. She's great.
-我為你跟烏蘇拉感到高興 -我覺得自己很幸運，她太棒了
-She's the most beautiful woman ever. -Thank you.
-她是最美麗的女人 -謝謝你
-Hey, Joey? -Yeah?
-喬伊 -什麼事？
-You read comic books, right? -Exclusively.
-你看漫畫書吧？ -我是專家
Who would win in a fight, Catwoman or Supergirl?
如果貓女跟女超人打架 誰會贏呢？
-Catwoman, hands down. -Yeah.
-當然是貓女 -太棒了
Between you and Phoebe? I'd give Phoebe the edge.
但你跟菲比嗎？ 我賭菲比會贏
-What? Really? -You kidding?
-什麼？真的嗎？ -你在開玩笑嗎？
Phoebe lived on the street, okay? Plus, she's got a crazy temper.
菲比在街上混過，好嗎？ 而且她生起氣來跟瘋婆子一樣
She's not right behind me, is she?
她沒有站在我後面吧？
No, you're fine.
不，你很安全
-Could I take Rachel? -I'm not sure.
-我能打倒瑞秋嗎？ -我不確定
What? Come on, I am tough!
什麼？少來了，我很凶的
Punch me here, as hard as you can!
用力打我這裡
Relax. Why are you so serious? It doesn't matter.
別激動，你為什麼那麼認真？ 那不重要
Really? What if I told you Ross or Chandler could beat you up?
真的嗎？如果我告訴你 羅斯或錢德能打倒你呢？
I would say, "Woman, please."
我會說「拜託，女人家」
Ursula's fiance is really sweet.
烏蘇拉的未婚夫真的很帥
-You think you could take him? -The dude with the balls on his chest?
-你覺得你能打倒他嗎？ -胸口貼著球的那個傢伙？
I think so.
我想可以
But what is he doing with my sister? He's so great.
但他跟我姐姐在一起做什麼？ 他真的太棒了
He's a teacher, he does volunteer work.
他是老師 他會做義工
Normally, I don't like sweaty guys. But I could just mop him up.
通常我不喜歡會流汗的男人 但我願意幫他擦汗
-Oh, my God, Phoebe? -What?
-天啊，菲比 -什麼？
-You're getting a crush on him. -No, I'm not, you are!
-你在暗戀他 -不，我才沒有，是你
Here comes the temper.
她的脾氣來了
Trick or treat.
不給糖就搗蛋
Know what? We're out of candy. But someone went for more.
你知道嗎？我們沒有糖果了 但已經有人去買了
And I've been giving out money, but I'm out of that too.
我改給孩子們錢 但我的錢也都給光了
-Can I write you a check? -Okay.
-我可以開張支票給你嗎？ -好吧
-Okay. What's your name? -Lelani Mayolanofavich.
-好吧，你叫什麼名字？ -李蘭妮馬尤拉諾法維奇
Okay, I'm just gonna write this out to "cash."
好吧，我會寫上 「現金支票」
-Hi. -Hi, Mona.
-嗨 -嗨，蒙娜
Joey's gonna be thrilled. He was hoping you'd be a slutty nurse.
喬伊一定會很興奮 他希望你扮成風流護士
Actually, I'm just a nurse.
事實上我只是扮成護士
You'd think that would embarrass me, but I'm maxed out.
你以為我聽了會覺得很丟臉 但我已經丟夠臉了
-You made it. -Wait.
-你來了 -等一下
-You're a potato? -Well, I'm a spud..?
-你是馬鈴薯？ -喔，我是波特多…
-And the antenna.. You're Spud-nik! -Yes!
-還有天線…你是波特多尼克 -答對了
Marry her.
娶她吧
Here's a good one. Who'd win a fight between Ross and Chandler?
這真的很有趣 羅斯跟錢德打架誰會贏？
I can't answer that. Chandler's my husband.
我沒辦法回答 錢德是我的老公
-So Ross? -Yeah.
-羅斯會贏？ -對
-Hey, beautiful. -Hello, handsome.
-嘿，美女 -哈囉，帥哥
Oh, God.
天啊
Look at you two. When did you guys meet?
看看你們兩個 你們什麼時候認識的？
-Two weeks ago. -That's it?
-兩個星期前 -就那樣？
I know. It sounds crazy, and I'm not impulsive, but..
我知道這聽起來很瘋狂 我不是個衝動的人，但是…
-we have so much in common. -Oh, really?
-我們有很多共通點 -真的嗎？
We're both teachers.
我們都是老師
-And we were both in the Peace Corps. -Peace Corps, really?
-我們都參加了和平工作團 -真的嗎？
When we were building in Uruguay, we were two towns apart and never met.
我們在烏拉圭做義工時 只距離兩個小鎮遠，卻從來沒見過面
Yeah. It wasn't a town when I got there, but it was a town when I left.
對，我剛到時那裡一片荒蕪 但我離開時那裡已經是個小鎮了
-Shall we get me really drunk? -Sure.
-我們可以去喝一杯嗎？ -沒問題
Howdy, doodie.
你好，糞團
That's funny, yeah.
那真的很有趣
You're the funniest man here in a bunny costume his wife made him wear.
你是個最幽默的傢伙 穿著你太太幫你挑的兔子裝
Relax, man. You're looking a little flushed.
別激動 你看起來有點要化掉了
-Our question might get answered. -What question?
-我們的問題有解了 -什麼問題？
Who could kick whose ass in a fight, you or Ross?
你跟羅斯打架 誰會贏？
-There's no question. -So you think Ross too?
-那不是問題 -你也覺得羅斯會贏？
-You picked Ross? -Ross is strong.
-你選羅斯？ -羅斯很強壯
He's the strongest out of all three of you. Except for Joey.
他是你們三個之中最壯的 喬伊除外
-I can't believe you didn't pick me. -She's right. I am stronger.
-我不敢相信你沒有選我 -她說的對，我比你壯
I would destroy you.
我要毀了你
Really? You think you're stronger? Why don't you prove it?
真的嗎？你覺得你比較壯嗎？ 你為什麼不證明給大家看？
I'll prove it like a theorem!
我一定會證明的
All right! Stop it!
好了，別吵了
Stop! No one's gonna fight.
別吵了，誰都不准打架
People came to see a fight, let's give them one!
大家來這裡看人打架 快打給他們看吧
-You guys could arm-wrestle. -Listen to the slutty nurse.
-你們可以比腕力 -聽風流護士的話
-You're going down. -Oh, yeah? You're going downtown!
-你死定了 -是嗎？你才死定了
Seriously, guys, the trash talk is embarrassing.
說真的 你們的叫陣台詞太遜了
Gunther, you brought candy. Thank you so much.
阿甘，你買到糖果了 謝謝你
-You are so sweet. -Really?
-你真的是太棒了 -真的嗎？
You are gonna make some man the luckiest guy in the world.
跟你在一起的人 會是全世界最幸運的男朋友
-Got to go. -Trick or treat.
-我得走了 -不給糖就搗蛋
Hi! Wow! There you go.
嗨，拿去吧
My friend Lewis told me you were giving out money.
我朋友路易斯說 你會給錢
We were, but now we've got candy.
沒錯，但現在我們有糖果了
I'd rather have the money.
我寧願要錢
That's not your choice. Happy Halloween!
那由不得你來選 萬聖節快樂
This isn't fair.
這不公平
Is it fair that you put on a cape and get stuff?
你披上斗篷就能跟別人要東西 那公平嗎？
Shut up!
閉嘴
You shut up!
你才閉嘴
-You can't tell me to shut up. -I think I just did.
-你不能叫我閉嘴 -我想我剛剛說了
And here it comes again. Shut up!
我又想說了，閉嘴
No, I got it. I'm good. I got it.
不，我可以，我很厲害的
Wait, I had one more thing to say. Right. Shut up.
等一下，我還有一句話要告訴你 對，閉嘴
You're a mean old woman.
你是個可怕的老女人
Wait! Shut.. Don't cry!
等一下，閉…別哭了
Let me get my checkbook!
我去拿支票簿
You don't have to do this. The strength inside you means the most.
你不必這麼做 心地善良才是最重要的
You're loyal, you're honest and you have integrity.
你既忠心又老實 而且你的品德高貴
That's the strength I want in a man.
那才是我要的男人
That means nothing to me. Come on!
那對我來說毫無意義，來吧
-Hi, liar. -Hey.
-嗨，騙子 -嘿
He's marrying you because he thinks the things you were saying were true.
他會娶你是因為 他以為你說的話是真的
-They could be true. -But they're not.
-它們有可能是真的 -但你真的在說謊
It's a fine line.
真假只有一線之隔
-Why are you lying? -I don't know.
-你為什麼要說謊？ -我不知道
He did this stuff, I said I did it too. He got so excited, it was fun.
他做了那些事，我說我也是 他變得很興奮，我覺得很好玩
You can't do this. You're gonna ruin his life.
你不能那麼做 你會毀了他的生活
Why are you taking this so seriously? It's just a marriage.
你為什麼那麼認真？ 這只是婚姻而已
Besides, if I cheat on him, I can call it an affair.
而且如果我背著他偷人 我可以說那是外遇
Honey?
甜心
It's a disgusting habit, and I want you to quit now!
這是個壞習慣 我要你馬上戒煙
She's helped so many people quit.
她幫助很多人戒煙
We'd better get going.
我們得走了
-You have a church group meeting. -Right.
-你還得參加教會的聚會 -對
-It was nice meeting you. -You too.
-很高興能見到你 -我也是
And, Ursula, it was really nice meeting you tonight!
烏蘇拉 我很高興今晚能見到你
Come on! Bunny versus doodie. We're waiting!
快來吧，兔子大戰糞團 我們在等你
Okay, guys. One match, winner take all.
好吧，一次決勝負 贏的人是英雄
Wait. What does the winner get?
等一下，冠軍有什麼獎品？
-Pride. -And dignity.
-驕傲 -跟自尊
Okay, if you say so.
好吧，你說了算
All right, ready, set, go!
好吧，就位，預備，開始
-Come on! -Come on!
-加油 -加油
-Wow, they're both really strong. -Or equally weak.
-他們都很壯 -或是一樣遜
Oh, God. Chandler's making his sex face.
天啊 錢德露出他的性感表情了
-So you getting tired? -No. I could do this all day.
-你累了嗎？ -不，我可以撐一整天
Yeah. Me too.
對，我也是
-Getting a little tired, though. -God, I'm exhausted.
-但我有點累了 -天啊，我累壞了
This is starting to look bad for me, okay? Mona's standing right there.
我開始漏氣了，好嗎？ 蒙娜就站在那裡
She's talking to Joey! You gotta let me win!
她在跟喬伊說話 你得讓我贏
Let me win. My wife thinks I'm a wimp.
讓我贏 我太太以為我是三腳貓
At least you have a wife. I get divorces and knock people up.
至少你還有太太 我離婚了，還搞大別人的勝子
And I'm dressed as doodie.
我打扮的跟個傻瓜一樣
-You're Spud-nik. -Come on, who we kidding? I'm doodie.
-你是波特多尼克 -少來了，我們要騙誰呢？我是傻瓜
Please? She's watching.
拜託，她在看我
-Fine. -Thanks.
-好吧 -謝謝
-Oh, no. -Oh, yeah!
-不 -太棒了
My hero!
我的英雄
You're a weird lady.
你是個怪女人
Ursula said she left her purse.
烏蘇拉忘了拿皮包
What a relief. It has the numbers for her prayer chain.
這真的是太好了 裡面放了她祈禱團朋友的電話
I'm sure it does.
是啊
Guess I'll see you at the wedding.
我們婚禮上見了
I don't think I'm gonna make it to the wedding.
我想我沒辦法 去參加婚禮
I wish you all the luck in the world.
祝你們好運
And I also want to give you a little piece of advice..
我還要給你 一個小建議
that I give to everyone who's getting married.
我會給每對新人 這樣的建議
Don't trust your wife.
別相信你的太太
I think we'll be okay.
我想我們會沒事的
It's so perfect, and she's been saving herself for me.
它真的太完美了 她一直為我保持處子之身
-I can't let you do this. She's lying. -What?
-我不能讓你這麼做，她在說謊 -什麼？
She is lying. And I bet I could prove it. Excuse me.
她在說謊 我想我可以證明，對不起
Okay. Yeah, not a prayer chain.
好吧，沒有祈禱團的電話
But what looks like a detailed drawing of a bank floor plan.
但它看起來像是 銀行的平面圖
Here's the name tag from where she works as a waitress.
這是她在餐廳 當女服務生的名牌
Not a teacher, a waitress.
她不是老師，她是女服務生
Here, she always lies about this.
拿去，她總是會撒這個謊
-How old did she say she was? -She told me she was 25.
-她跟你說她幾歲了？ -她說她25歲
I almost don't want to show you.
我真的不想拿給你看
Just remember, I'm a minute younger.
記住，我比她年輕一分鐘
I am so stupid.
我太笨了
Of course she's not a teacher.
她當然不是老師
There's no such thing as a "Top Secret School for the Children of Spies."
根本不會有 「超機密兒童間諜學校」
No, you're not stupid.
不，你不笨
I'm not smart.
我不聰明
I just wanted so much to be impulsive for once.
我只是很想 衝動一下
-To be romantic. -Good.
-找一點浪漫 -很好
You should be impulsive and romantic. You did it with the wrong person.
你應該要衝動跟浪漫 只是你找錯對象了
-What? -It's weird, two people look so alike.
-什麼？ -那真的很奇怪，你們長得那麼像
And so different.
卻完全不一樣
Eric! Let's go!
艾力克，我們走吧
-Better go deal with it. -Yeah, you should.
-我得去解決問題 -沒錯，你該那麼做
Hurry up! I gotta pray!
快點，我得去禱告
I had to give the kid 50 bucks to stop crying.
我得給那孩子50塊 他才不哭
That's not bad.
那還不賴
I also had to go to a few houses as his girlfriend.
我還得當他的女朋友 陪他走一段路
I am awful with children.
我真的不會應付小孩子
You're good with kids. They're just crazy on Halloween.
你跟孩子們相處的很好 只是小孩子在萬聖節都會抓狂
They're all greedy, hopped up on sugar.
他們貪心地 想多拿一些糖果
-That's all it is? -Absolutely.
-就那樣？ -當然
Halloween is the worst. Except for Christmas. And their birthdays.
萬聖節是最糟糕的 除了耶誕節跟他們的生日
They get crazy during the summer too.
他們在暑假也會抓狂
And any time they're hungry or sleepy.
還有他們勝子餓 跟想睡覺的時候
Kids are tough. Good luck with that.
小孩子很難纏 祝你好運
Look, I'm sorry you lost.
聽著，我很遺憾你輸了
I got a secret for you. I let him win.
我得告訴你一個秘密 我放水讓他贏
Was that a secret, or a lie?
那是秘密還是謊話？
-No, I let him.. Ross? -Yeah?
-不，我讓他…羅斯 -什麼事？
Would you tell her I let you win, please?
麻煩你告訴她 我放水讓你贏
Chandler "let me win."
錢德「放水讓我贏」
No, Chandler's really strong. My arm is so sore. Oh, nurse?
不，錢德真的好壯 我的手好酸喔，護士
I am strong. I'll show you.
我很強壯，我要證明給你看
Chandler, please.
錢德，拜託
What's the matter? Scared?
怎麼了？你害怕嗎？
Let's go, big bunny!
來吧，大兔子
One, two, three. Go!
一，二，三，開始
I'm gonna kill myself!
我要去自殺